Guide to the Stanford University, English Club, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, English Club, records
1901-1945
SC0854
Stanford University. English Club.
1.75 Linear feet (4 boxes)
Records include minutes 1901-1937; constitution, 1929 and 1935; correspondence, mailings, and announcements, 1932-1945; programs, clippings, and articles about the club's drama productions, 1903-1934; and extra copies of several of the club's publications. Included among the minutes are photographs (mostly of drama productions or cast members), programs, correspondence, copyright registration for First Year at Stanford (1905), and short historical notes on the Club.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
The records were received via administrative transfer in 1965.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The English Club, a student organization at Stanford, was organized in February 1901. Its activities included round tables, lectures, publication of original student work, and the production of plays.
Description of the Collection
The records include minutes 1901-1937; constitution, 1929 and 1935; correspondence, mailings, and announcements, 1932-45; programs, clippings, and articles about the club's drama productions, 1903-1934; and extra copies of several of the club's publications. Included among the minutes are photographs (mostly of drama productions or cast members), programs, correspondence, copyright registration for First Year at Stanford (1905), and short historical notes on the Club.
Access Terms
Stanford University. English Club.; College and school drama; Playbills
Collection Contents
- Minute book (bound), 1901-1925 (Box 1)
  In addition to minutes, this book includes includes photographs (mostly of drama productions or cast members), programs, correspondence, copyright registration for First Year At Stanford (1905), and short historical notes on the Club
- Minutes, 1925-1930 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Minutes, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Minutes, 1932-summer 1934 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Minutes, Oct. 1934-June 1935 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Minutes, Oct. 1935-Feb. 1937 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Constitution, 1929, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1932-34 and undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Mailings, announcements (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Publications - announcements (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Clarence Urmy Poetry Prize announcements, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- History of the club (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Photographs (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Knight of the Burning Pestle, programs, clippings, etc., 1903 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Knight of the Burning Pestle, original clippings, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Every Man in His Humour, programs, clippings, etc., 1905 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Every Man in His Humour, original clippings, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Clipping on club's drama productions, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Three Miracle Plays, programs etc., 1911 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Justice, program etc., 1917 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Stanford Pageant "Service," programs, preliminary outline, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- If I Were King, programs etc., 1922 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Programs for assorted plays, 1908-1925 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Programs for assorted plays, 1928-1934 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Extra copies of the club's publication: A Year Book of Stanford Writing, 1930-1939 (Box 3)
- Extra copies of the club's publications: On Seeing an Elizabethan Play, 1903; Elizabethan Humours and the Comedy of Ben Jonson, 1905; The First Year at Stanford, 1905 and 1910; and A Stanford Book of Verse 1912-1916, 1916 (Box 4)